# Sam Kritchevsky

GitHub | LinkedIn | sam.kritch@gmail.com | 336-414-8694

#### **ABOUT ME**

I'm a data generalist and backend engineer, with 5 years of experience working across a modern cloud-based data stack, and a strong math background. I'm looking for a role where I can have impact with my current skillset, while gaining experience with full-stack data-intensive products, MLops, or statistical inference and forecasting.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Languages** : Python, Scala, SQL, some Javascript / Typescript

Technologies : PostgreSQL, Redshift, Elasticsearch, Redis, PostGIS, Spark, Flink, RabbitMQ, Akka, DBT, Docker, No-

mad, Datadog, Grafana, AWS, EMR, Lambda, Kinesis, S3, Neptune, Jupyter, Luigi, Dagster

Roles : Data Science, Data Engineering, Data Platform, Backend, Analytics, ML Engineering

### **EXPERIENCE**

SeatgeekNew York, NYSr. Software Engineer, Data Platform, Tech Lead2020-2021

Tech lead of team of six engineers. Projects included:

• Rewrite of our in-house event ingestion service in Flink + Kafka to add features, modernize, and scale to bursts of high traffic. I advocated for the project, designed the system, and implemented much of the business logic.

- \* Fanouts to front page recommendations, push notifications, and Redshift, with plans to support an online feature store.
- \* Realtime sessionization, with handling of late-arriving data.
- \* Validation against a repository of JSONSchemas, with alerting in Datadog
- Deployed Amundsen, an OSS data-discovery platform, with a custom AWS Neptune backend.
- Jupyter infrastructure based on Docker, Papermill, and NBViewer.

We also owned the core data stack: <u>Druzhba</u> (built-in-house ETL), DBT, Looker, Luigi, Redshift, and other AWS products.

Sr. Data Scientist 2019-2020

Data Scientist II 2018

I specialized in user recommendation signals and our event catalog, working in Spark, SQL, and Python. Projects included:

- Algorithms for the weekly newsletter, cart abandonment and price drops notifications, in Spark + SQL. This tripled the direct revenue of the weekly newsletter immediately.
- Event and performer popularity models for event recommendations and search, built with Keras
- Entity-linking algorithm deduplicating users and device for marketing attribution and funnel KPIs.
- Ongoing involvement in the design and measurement of recommendation, search, and CRM marketing.

Software Engineer, Discovery

Sept 2016-2017

Location: New York, NY

I built features for search, CRM marketing, and frontpage recommendations.

#### Other

Greater Harlem Coalition (Volunteer)

2022-

Contributed data analysis, writing, editing, and website administration for a community advocacy group. My data pipeline uses DBT, Dagster, and PostGIS (code <u>here</u>.)

Physics Teaching Assistant 2014-2016

# **EDUCATION**

University of Wisconsin

**University of North Carolina** 

Madison, WI 2013-2015

Coursework towards Physics Ph.D.

Chapel Hill, NC

B.S. Physics

2012